# Ronald Sáenz

• Toronto, ON, Canada M6A 0B1

• Contact: +1 647 803 4678 • Email Address: ronaldsaenz88@gmail.com

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Thirteen years experienced software developer, strong programming experience in Python, PHP, JAVA, PostgreSQL, MySQL and Oracle Databases, developing web applications, web services and scripts, participating in the technical design, development, and implementation of systems, using principles of Object-Oriented Analysis and Design. Five years of experience in secure software development and Secure SDLC. One year of experience in cloud environment, DevOps, and Infrastructure as code. Fast learner and able to effectively self-manage during projects, demonstrating strong organizational and estimation skills. Ability to produce quality work in a timely manner.

# **SKILLS**

- Ability to solve problems and teach others.
- Strong organizational and estimation skills.
- · Ability to work in a team.
- Ability to get results in a fast paced environment.
- Ability to work independently as well as coordinate efforts with other team members.

#### TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

- Programming Language: Python, PHP, JAVA, Perl, Shell, Bash, Terraform, Ansible, Javascript
- Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, Oracle.
- Frameworks: Django, Flask, Symfony.
- Web Services: Nusoap, Restful API
- Virtualization: Docker, Kubernetes
- SIEMs: Splunk, ELK
- Cybersecurity Management based on standard: ISO22301, 27001, PCI-DSS
- Organizational Tools: JIRA, Confluence
- Version Control and CI/CD: Gitlab, Github
- · Operating System: Linux, Windows

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Cloud DevOps Engineer**

May 2021 - Present

Flugel.it • US • Remote

Responsible for developing new cloud solutions following established technical design, application development standards and quality processes for clients. The concept infrastructure as code is used every day in all implementations, for that I used the languages Terraform, Ansible, Go. I used GitHub or GitLab actions to include CI/CD which it allows to include the deployment the environment using Docker or Kubernetes. Additionally, I used different unit test in all developments, for instance: pylint, pytest, kube-linter, etc. Also, I developed some web applications using Django or Flask Framework in Python.

Database Administration: MySQL and PostgreSQL

# **Security Engineer**

Feb 2017 - May 2021

Telconet • Guayaquil

Responsible for developing new solutions following established technical design, application development standards and quality processes for internal applications in the Security area, for which a web application is developed to manage the company's cybersecurity incidents. In addition, a web platform for asset management platform is created that integrates with the management of technical vulnerabilities. The development of some integration scripts with computer security tools (Firewalls, IDS/IPS, Nessus, Arbor, Splunk SIEM, Mail Firewalls). Management of WAF (Web Application Firewall) tools for internal web servers and clients.

Work with version control systems and continuous integration systems (GIT, Sonar).

Design some web applications using Python

Develop scripts using Python

Database Administration: MySQL and PostgreSQL

#### **Senior Developer**

Nov 2013 - Feb 2017

Telconet • Guayaquil

Responsible for developing new solutions following established technical design, application development standards and quality processes for internal applications in the Networking area, for which it was necessary to execute configurations in switches and routers to be able to provide Internet services to customers of the company. In addition, a Middleware (Web Services) is created to integrate with the company's CRM.

Work with version control systems and continuous integration systems (GIT, Sonar).

Design some web applications using Python

Develop scripts using Python and Perl

Database Administration: MySQL, PostgreSQL and Oracle

## **Junior Developer**

Jul 2012 - Oct 2013

Telconet • Guayaquil

Responsible for developing new solutions following application development standards and quality processes for applications for CRM platform in the telecommunication company.

Work with version control systems and continuous integration systems (GIT, Sonar).

Design some web applications using PHP and Python

Database Administration: MySQL and Oracle

# **Junior Developer**

Jul 2010 - Jun 2012

GEA Ecuador • Guayaquil

Responsible for developing new solutions following application development standards and quality processes for internal applications.

Design some web applications using PHP

Develop scripts using Python Database Administration: MySQL

Junior Developer

Jan 2010 - Jul 2010

E-Technology • Guayaquil

**Junior Developer** 

Mar 2009 – Jul 2010

Palosanto Solutions • Guayaquil

## **EDUCATION**

### **Cybersecurity Master's Degree**

Mar 2016 - Mar 2018

Escuela Superior Politécnica del Litoral • Guayaquil

# **Diploma in Project Management**

Feb 2011 - Sep 2011

Universitat de Valencia • Guayaquil

#### **Computer Engineering**

Mar 2006 - Mar 2011

Universidad Católica Santiago de Guayaquil • Guayaquil

#### PROFESSIONAL CREDENTIALS

- SFPC Scrum Foundation Professional Certificate
- Certified Ethical Hacker (CEH)
- Certified NSE 1 Network Security Associate Fortinet
- Radware Certified Application Specialist on Alteon (RCAS-AL)
- Radware Certified Security Specialist on DefensePro with APSolute Vision\*TM (RCSS)
- Radware Certified Application Security Specialist on AppWall (RCAScS)